SAM HALL

Technology Consultant





CONTACT



sammchall@gmail.com

EXPERTISE



Design Methods and Processes

Programming

User Interface

Visual Communication

SKILLS



Hard Skills
Adobe CC
HTML, CSS, JS
Sketch, InVision

Soft Skills

Communication

Empathy

Colloboration



PROFILE

Hi there! My name is Sam. I'm a recent graduate of Design Computing at the University of Sydney. During my degree, I discovered a passion for creating enjoyable and meaningful experiences that become part of people's everyday lives. My passionate is wellbeing and learning design. I enjoy working in this space with teams comprised of individuals with unique perspectives and a like-minded goal to bring about innovation.



EXPERIENCE

ASSOCIATE TECHNOLOGY CONSULTANT Jun 2018 - Present ACCENTURE TECHNOLOGY

As a technology consultant, I've found the keys for success to be an understanding of stakeholder needs and pain points as well as their effective communication, the utilization and collation of subject matter expertise from various experts and building a strategic framework around the software development lifecycle. I've found that through the efficient and effective implementation of these concepts, a relationship of trust and success is built between a technology consultant and their client.

WEB DESIGN DEMONSTRATOR

Jun 2017 - Jun 2018

THE UNIVERSITY OF SYDNEY

As a demonstrator, I have learnt to quickly grasp how to speak to large groups in an energetic and educational way. In contrast, I would also speak to students one on one; covering content in a more conversational way. Honing these styles of communication has helped me to better read a room and understand the priorities when conveying understanding.

SALES REPRESENTATIVE

Jun 2016 - Dec 2016

LANGTONS WINE BROKERAGE

As a sales specialist, I learnt the fundamentals of a sales pitch. It was enjoyable working for a company that really invested in the customer. I learnt to quickly comprehend the customers needs; both conscious and subconscious. I could then give them easy to understand information about the product that suited them. This took the hassle of the overabundance of choice out of their experience.

ROWING COACH

Nov 2014 - Mar 2016

NEWCASTLE GRAMMAR SCHOOL

As a rowing coach at Newcastle Grammar School, I taught young people to work as a team and develop physical and mental fitness. The most important takeaway from my time coaching was learning how to motivate people in time sensitive situations.



EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF DESIGN COMPUTING

Mar 2015 - Mar 2018

THE UNIVERSITY OF SYDNEY

This degree has fostered my passion to create enjoyable and meaningful experiences. I've realised UX Design is a path to create something that can change peoples lives for the better. The skills I've learnt have allowed me to transform my goals into actionable steps to more efficiently and effectively create a change for the better.

SAM HALL

Technology Consultant





CONTACT



sammchall@gmail.com

HOBBIES



Surfing Video Games Martial Arts Singing

PASSIONS



Create

Discover

Connect

Empower



AWARDS/ACHIEVEMENTS

PUBLIC VALUE DESIGN AWARD

D₁₇ GRADUATION SHOW

SCHOLARSHIP OF I.T

ST ANDREWS COLLEGE

SCHOLARSHIP OF VOICE

ST ANDREWS COLLEGE

GOLD MEDAL

2014 NSW ROWING CHAMPIONSHIPS

SILVER MEDAL

2012 AUSTRALIAN ROWING CHAMPIONSHIPS

GOLD MEDAL

2011 AUSTRALIAN ROWING CHAMPIONSHIPS

SCHOLARSHIP OF VOICE

NEWCASTLE GRAMMAR SCHOOL



LEADERSHIP/CONTRIBUTIONS

FOUNDING MEMBER

CULTURAL DIVERSITY PROJECT

VICE PRESIDENT

SYDNEY UNI KENPO KARATE

FRONTMAN

BRASS RAZOO

PREFECT AND HOUSE CAPTAIN

NEWCASTLE GRAMMAR SCHOOL